A Guide to the Charles Mcclure Papers, 1866-1940
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Charles Mcclure Papers 1866-1940
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1765
This collection consists of ca. 2000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
Personal, family, and business correspondence, and letters to government officials and journalists reflect McClure's interest in Australia, international affairs particularly World War I and the League of Nations, agriculture, commerce and economics. Frederic J. Haskin and Yandell Henderson are correspondents and there are brief or routine responses from John H. Clarke, Homer S. Cummings, Walter Lippmann, Felix Morley, William S. Shepherd, and Oscar W. Underwood.
Other topics include local affairs in Warren County, Va., particularly Calvary Episcopal Church, Front Royal and the management of "Moreland"; and the papers of George F. Viett of Norfolk, Va.
In addition the collection contains miscellaneous writings, a diary and a letterbook kept while working for H.W. Peabody and Company, Sydney, a scrapbook, and a 1928 rain map of New South Wales.
Contents List
- Personal Correspondence
  - Correspondence of the McClure and related families 1869-1936 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Robert E. Auld 1926-1936 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Fanny Bucknell 1924-1929 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Mr. and Mrs. Stephen Eliot Bullard 1913-1939 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and John H. Clark 1924 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and William H. Frothingham 1920-1931 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Sidney V. and Helen (McClure) Haas, and their son Gilbert 1924-1940 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Leonard M. Hansford 1922 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Jeannette Kelly 1923-1926 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Robert Morse Lovett 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and his nephew, Charles McClure 1935 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and his brother, George McClure 1885-1930 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and his brother, John McClure 1913-1931 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and his nephew, John M. McClure 1917-1939 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and his sister-in-law, Keziah McClure 1930-1934 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and his nephew, Warwick McClure 1921-1935 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and J. Roberts 1920-1931 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Linda W. Roberts 1920-1939 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Mrs. Douglas Robinson 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and W. E. Carson 1926-1930 (Box 1)
  - Letters from Charles McClure to Mrs. Carson 1921 (Box 1)
  - Letters from Charles McClure to his Aunt Janet 1870-1932 (Box 1)
  - Letters from Charles McClure to Mr. Rowland 1937-1939 (Box 1)
  - Memorandum Re: family affairs and incident of 1913 1922-1931 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence of Charles McClure 1915-1940 (Box 2)
- Business Correspondence
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Alfred Fraser Inc. 1920-1930 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the government of Australia 1919-1936 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Bloch and Hirsch Fur Company 1925-1926 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Daddario and Company 1925 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Dalgety and Company Limited 1921-1926 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and E. V. Connett and Company 1923-1924 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Gordon and Ferguson 1919-1927 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Hitchcock, Dermody and Company 1920-1926 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Hormann and Wormald 1920-1939 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Isaac A. Schoen and Sons 1920-1926 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and John F. Kaiser Inc. 1924-1925 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Lawrence and Johnson Company 1929 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Legallet, Hellwig, Norton Company 1920-1926 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Logan and Fairburn 1920 (Box 2)
  - (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Nathan Berlin 1925-1928 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and New York Auction Company Inc. 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Ode Comeau Company 1920-1922 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Philip A. Feinberg Inc. 1928-1930 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Pittsburgh Wool Company 1925 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Scott, Henderson and Company 1922-1939 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Strumeyer, Son and Ladenheim Skins 1921-1923 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the U.S. Post Office 1922-1927 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the Waring Hat Manufacturing Company 1921-1925 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and William Matsner and Company 1919-1930 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Ziegal, Eisman and Company 1920-1932 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Business Associations 1923-1925 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Editors of Newspapers and Magazines 1917-1940, (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Business Papers 1897-1940 (Box 3)
- Agriculture
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and C. Fred Berry 1940 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the Department of Agriculture 1917-1940 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the Department of Commerce 1922-1931 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the Federal Farm Board 1930-1940 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the State Departments of Agriculture 1918-1928 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence Re: Agriculture 1917-1940 (Box 3)
  - Agricultural Economics 1920-1940 (Box 3)
  - Apple Market 1925-1932 (Box 3)
  - Australian Skins 1919-1936 (Box 3)
  - Cotton and Wool Comparison 1915-1940 (Box 3)
  - Field Crop Production and Marketing 1916-1940 (Box 3)
  - McClure Farm 1922-1936 (Box 3)
  - New Crops 1922-1936 (Box 3)
- Economics
  - American Telephone and Telegraph 1919-1939 (Box 4)
  - Conditions in America 1919-1939 (Box 4)
  - Cooperative Stores in New Zealand 1918-1919 (Box 4)
  - Finance 1921-1938 (Box 4)
  - International Matters 1921-1938 (Box 4)
  - International Trade 1915-1940 (Box 4)
  - Oil 1920-1921 (Box 4)
  - Rubber 1925-1934 (Box 4)
  - Shipping 1921-1939 (Box 4)
  - Stock Market Reports 1922-1938 (Box 4)
  - Tariffs 1920-1934 (Box 4)
  - United States Steel 1921-1924 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Economic Topics 1920-1932 (Box 4)
- Foreign Relations
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the British Library of Information 1918-1940 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Frederic J. Haskin 1926-1940 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Yandell Henderson 1928 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and the Overseas Club 1918-1922 (Box 4)
  - America and Asia 1922-1927 (Box 5)
  - American Colonies 1921-1924 (Box 5)
  - Australia and New Zealand 1919-1939 (Box 5)
  - Australia and the United States: Relative Size 1921-1927 (Box 5)
  - Belgian Relief Commission 1917-1928 (Box 5)
  - European War Debts 1917-1940, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - Lindbergh's Flight 1927-1930 (Box 5)
  - Post World War I Policy of American Rights 1921-1940 (Box 5)
  - Relations between United Kingdom and the United States 1917-1927 (Box 5)
  - Tonnage of Vessels 1925-1939 (Box 6)
  - World War I and League of Nations 1917-1940 (Box 6)
  - World War II 1938-1940 (Box 6)
- Religion
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Church Officials and others 1914-1940 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence between Charles McClure and Religious Organizations 1920-1940 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence Re: Religious Matters 1922-1940 (Box 6)
  - Calvary Episcopal Church, Front Royal: Finances 1919-1940 (Box 6)
  - Calvary Episcopal Church, Front Royal: Membership 1916-1940 (Box 6)
  - Diocese of Virginia: Church Pension Fund 1916-1917 (Box 6)
  - Diocese of Virginia: Finances 1920-1934 (Box 6)
  - Episcopal Church: Finances 1933-1937 (Box 6)
  - Episcopal Church: Membership 1932-1940 (Box 6)
  - Papers Re: Church and Religion 1922-1940 (Box 6)
  - Printed Material Re: Church and Religion 1916-1937 (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous Concerns
  - Bonds of the Southern States of America 1920-1939 (Box 7)
  - Circulars of Headquarters, Commandery No. I, Pennsylvania 1866-1867 (Box 7)
  - Crime: Correspondence and Related Papers 1920-1939 (Box 7)
  - Crime: Printed 1920-1938 (Box 7)
  - Education and Health Issues 1923-1940 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous 1910-1939 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Notes of Charles McClure n.d., (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1908-1940 (Box 7)
  - George F. Viett Papers ca. 1915-1937 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Climatology and Weather 1910-1918 (Box 8)
  - Virginia Miscellaneous 1919-1937 (Box 8)
  - Warren County Concerns 1917-1937 (Box 8)
  - Writings of Charles McClure 1920-1933 (Box 8)
- Bound Volumes
  - Diary kept by [Charles McClure?] 1883-1889 (Box 8)
  - Letterbook kept by Charles McClure 1881, 1888-1890 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings on Economics and other Topics 1909-1910 (Box 8)